A Guide to the Biology Department Collection, 1930-1998
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Biology Department Collection1930-1998
Special Collections, James Madison University
5038
2 boxes
Two large pictures and the contents of a scrapbook that contained public relations material from the Biology Department.
Biology Department, James Madison University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
JMU transfer from the department to Special Collections on June 11, 2012
Provenance
This material was transferred by the department secretary when the department moved to the new Bioscience Building. The collection includes two pictures that had been on the office walls.
Scope and Content
Cards, letters, and newspaper articles relating to events, the major figures in the Biology Department, or the Life Sciences Museum that was run by the biology department.
Includes handwritten notes on the pages from some of the people in the department who put together the scrapbook.
There are also two large photographs that came from the office walls of the department when the Biology Department moved to the new Biosciences Building.
Arrangement
The Collection is arranged in two series:
I: Scrapbook Pages - newspaper clippings, thank you cards, and notes arranged folders.
II: Photographs - were large wall hangings in the department office.
Contents List
- Scrapbook Pages
  - Page 1: newpaper clipping - 1983 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Page 2: newspaper clippings - 1983 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Page 3: newspaper clippings - 1984 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Page 4: newspaper clipping, brochure from Life Science Museum - 1984 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Page 5: Life Science Museum tour guide, list of bird species (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Page 6: 2 newspaper clippings, Life Science Museum tour guide - 1985 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Page 7: letter, newspaper clipping - 1985 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Page 8: 5 children's thank you cards, handwritten note - 1985 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Page 9: 9 children's thank you cards (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Page 10: 2 newspaper clippings - 1986 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Page 11: 2 newspaper clippings, drawing - 1986 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Page 12: school address, thank you note - 1984 (Box-folder 1:12)
    (Page 13 of the scrabook was blank)
  - Page 14: 3 handwritten thank you notes, caption - 1986 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Page 15: newspaper article - 1986 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Page 16: newspaper clipping - 1988 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Page 17: newspaper clipping (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Page 18: newspaper clipping - 1989 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Page 19: newspaper clipping, Life Sciences Museum brochure - 1991 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Page 20: 2 newspaper clippings, handwritten thank you note - 1992 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Page 21: newspaper clipping - 1992 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Page 22: 3 children's thank you cards (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Page 23: 2 newspaper clippings, handwritten thank you card - 1992 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Page 24: newspaper clipping - 1992 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Page 25: newspaper clipping - 1995 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Page 26: newspaper clipping - 1998 (Box-folder 1:25)
- Photographs
  - Moody Hall (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Unidentified elementary classroom (Box-folder 2:2)